American Philosophical Society Archives. Record Group IIh. 1892-1896 APS.Archives.IIh APS.Archives.IIh
American Philosophical Society
American Philosophical Society Archives. Record Group IIh
1892-1896
APS.Archives.IIh
American Philosophical Society
1.0 section
This is part of the large inventory for the American Philosophical Society Archives. For complete information concerning this collection, please view the Collection Description.
American Philosophical Society.
- Papers
  - Letter to Frederick Fraley, Jan. 3, 1892; 8x5; Roberts, John B. (John Bingham), 1852-1924
    Scope and Contents note
    Phila., A.L.S. 2p. Asks if his uncle, R.J. Levis, had actually proposed him for A.P.S. membership. Refers to S.W. Roberts, C.C. Roberts.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 5, 1892; 8-1/4x5-1/4; McIntosh, W.
    London, A.L.S. 1p., end. Asks for copy of membership list.
  - Letter to H[enry] Phillips, Jan. 7, 1892; 8x5; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 1p. Appoints committee to examine E.D. Cope's paper: J.A. Ryder, H.F. Jayne, B. Sharp.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jan. 8, 1892; 7x4-1/2; Potts, William John, 1842-1895
    Camden, N.J., A.L.S. 1p., end. Cannot attend next Library Committee meeting.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 9, [1892]; 7x4-1/2; Mitchell, Silas Weir
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 1p., end. Is not receiving notices of meetings.
  - Letter to the Secretaries of the A.P.S., Jan. 11, 1892; 9x5-1/2; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    Phila., A.L.S. 2p. Enc. wanting. Sends report of his committee on the publication of the Proceedings.
  - Letter to the [American philosophical society], Jan. 12, 1892; 11-1/2x9; Fock, Gustav
    Leipzig, A.L.S. 4p., end. In German. Offers library of F. Harncke for sale.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jan. 14, 1892; 11x8; Wayland, H. L. (Heman Lincoln), 1830-1898
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p. Declines membership in A.P.S.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, Jan. 16, 1892; 10x8-1/2; Wilson, William P. (William Powell), 1844-1927
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Refers to G.L. Goodale. Refers to matter at meeting on previous evening.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jan. 16, [1892]; 3-3/4x6-1/4; Schwab, Isidore
    [Phila.], A.L.S. on postal card 1p. and add. Cannot be at library today.
  - Letter to W[illiam] A[rmstrong] Ingham, Jan. 18, 1892; 7x4-1/2; Green, F. M. (Francis Mathews), b. 1835
    U.S.S. Saratoga, Phila., A.L.S. 3p., end., and end. Declines membership.
  - Letter to the Secretaries of the A.P.S., Jan. 19, 1892; 3x5; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    Phila., A.L.S. on postal card 1p., end. and add. Has sent report of Committee on Publication of the Proceedings to the printer, McCalla & Co.
  - Letter to [Henry Phillips], Jan. 19, 1892; 10-1/2x7-3/4; Wright, John, 1836-1919
    St. Paul, [Minn.], A.L.S. 1p. and end. Inquiry about A.P.S. Eliot Indian Bibles.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jan. 20, 1892; 10-3/4x8-1/4; Houston, Edwin J. (Edwin James), 1847-1914
    Phila., Typed L.S. with MS. additions. 1p. Has received appointment as Chairman of Library Committee. Gives Phillips authority to discharge employees.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, [Jan. 21, 1892]
    Postcard. Informing that Miss Morison is ill and that a doctor is attending. Thursday morning.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, Jan. 22, 1892; 9x5-3/4; Morris, J. Cheston (James Cheston), 1831-1923
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p., end. Is sending man to repair models and optical instruments.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jan. 24, 1892; 3x5; Morison, Ella M.
    [Phila.], A.L.S. on postal card 1p. and add. Health is better.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 26, 1892; 3x5; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    Phila., A.L.S. on postal card 1p., end., and add. Will read paper on origin of cranial arches in reptilia at next meeting. For printed paper, see: APS Transactions, vol. 17, pp.11-26.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jan. 26, 1892; 8x5; United States. Division of Forestry
    Washington, A.L.S.: N.H. Egleston 2p., end. Inquires about paper by Rothrock on "Some microscopic distinctions between good and bad timber of the same species." For paper, see: APS Proceedings, vol. 20, pp.599-604.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, Jan. 28, 1892; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Gregory, Henry Duval, 1819-1897
    Girard College, [Phila.], A.L.S. 1p., end. Refers to C.R. Gregory.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 29, 1892; 9x5-3/4; Campbell, J. L. (John Lyle), 1827-1904
    Crawfordsville, Ind., A.L.S. 1p., end. Enc. wanting. Sends his photograph.
  - Letter to [Henry] Philips [sic], Jan. 30, 1892; 7x4-1/2; Bonwill, William Gibson Arlington, 1833-1899
    Phila. A.L.S. 2p. Incomplete? Will read his paper on evolution on Feb. 5. Sends list of persons to be notified.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan., 1892; 13-1/2x8-1/2; Great Britain. Meteorological Office
    London, Printed L. filled in in MS. 1p., end. Enc. wanting. Inquires if A.P.S. wished to continue to receive its publications. Sends form to be filled out and returned.
  - Letter to [Henry] P[hillips], Jan., 1892; 8x5; Horn, George H. (George Henry), 1840-1897
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Concerns report of Cope's committee on publication of the Proceedings.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Feb. 2, 1892; 7x4-1/2; Potts, William John, 1842-1895
    Camden, N.J., A.L.S. 1p. Asks to be appointed to write obituary of J.F. Garrison.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Feb. 4, 1892; 8x5; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    Phila., L. 2p. Cannot attend next meeting. Suggests Dudley or Vaux to preside. Approves W.J. Potts to write obituary of J.F. Garrison.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Feb. 8, 1892; 8x5; Price, John Sergeant, 1831-1897
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Concerns appropriation for Journals and Binding.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Feb. 9, 1892; 10x8; Bowdoin College
    [Brunswick, Maine] Printed L. filled in in MS. and S.: Wm.D.W. Hyde, President, Geo. T. Little, Librarian. 1p. Acknowledges receipt of Proceedings, Nos.132-136.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Feb. 9, 1892; 9x5-3/4; Bowdoin College
    Brunswick, Maine, A.L.S.: Geo. T. Little, Libn. 1p., end. Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Feb. 9, 1892; 8x5; Mallet, John William
    Charlottesville, Va., A.L.S. 2p. Asks for copies of J.P. Lesley's papers on the geology of Virginia for a friend.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Feb. 9, 1892; 7x4-1/2; Potts, William John, 1842-1895
    Camden, N.J., A.L.S. 3p., end. Concerns obituary of J.F. Garrison.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Feb. 10, 1892; 5x8; Hall, James, 1811-1898
    Albany, Typed L.S. 1p., end. Concerns death of Andrew Ramsay.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Feb. 12, 1892; 8x5; Lee, William
    Washington, A.L.S. 1p., end. Announces death of T.J. Lee. Refers to Francis M. Lee.
  - Letter to the Secretaries of the A.P.S., Feb. 15, 1892; 3-3/4x6-1/4; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    Phila., A.L.S. on postal card 1p., end., and add. Will read paper on the geology of the Staked Plains of Texas at the next meeting. For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings, vol. 30, pp.123-131.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Feb. 15, 1892; 10-1/2x8; Smithsonian Institution
    Washington, Typed L. 1p. Concerns package for D. Rosa of Turin.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Feb. 15, 1892; 10x8; Lick Observatory
    Mount Hamilton, [Cal.], A.L.S.: Edward S. Holden. 1p., end. Thanks for gift of Proceedings.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Feb. 16, 1892; 8-3/4x5-1/2; Douglas, James, 1837-1918
    New York, A.L.S. 2p. Offers to write obituary of T.S. Hunt.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, Feb. 16, 1892; 8-1/2x11; Tacoma Academy of Science (Tacoma, Wash.)
    Tacoma, Wash., A.L.S.: W[illia]m Curtis Taylor, Cor. Sec. 1p. Thanks for publications. Refers to Phillips' editing of A.P.S. minutes, Proceedings, No. 119.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, Feb. 17, 1892; 8x5; Gatschet, Albert S. (Albert Samuel), 1832-1907
    Washington, A.L.S. 2p., end., and end. Corrects several errors in sketch of Emma Seiler. For printed sketch, see: APS Proceedings vol.29, pp.151-162.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Feb. 21, [1892]; 3-3/4x6-1/4; Brinton, Daniel Garrison, 1837-1899
    Phila., A.L.S. on postal card 1p., end., and add., end. Asks for meeting of Publication Committee.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Feb. 22, 1892; 8x5; University of Cincinnati
    Cincinnati, O., A.L.S.: W.E. Waters, Librarian. 2p., end. Thanks for publications.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Feb. 22, 1892; 10-3/4x8-1/2; Koloniaal Museum te Haarlem
    Haarlem, L. 1p., end. Exchange of Publications.
  - Letter to the [American philosophical society;], Feb. 23, [1892]; 3-3/4x5-3/4; Schwarz, J. H.
    Kladno, A.L.S. on postal card 1p., end., and add. In German. Asks for receipt for book and letter.
  - Letter to Henry Philips [sic], Feb. 23, 1892; 3x5; Bonwill, William Gibson Arlington, 1833-1899
    Phila., A.L.S. on postal card 1p. and add., end. Concerns reading of his paper on evolution. Refers to E.D. Cope.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Feb. 23, 1892; 10-1/2x8; Smithsonian Institution
    Washington, Typed L. 1p. Has no record of an unnamed man.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Feb. 23, 1892; 3x5; United States Civil Service Commission
    Washington, Printed L. on postal card 1p., end., and add. Offers set of its reports.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips [sic], Feb. 25, 1892; 10-3/4x8; Douglas, James, 1837-1918
    New York, Typed L.S. 1p., end. Concerns his sketch of T.S. Hunt.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Feb. 25, 1892; 3x5; Patterson, Robert, 1819-1909
    Phila., A.L.S. on postal card 1p. and add. Concerns Franklin Peale collection of Stone Age relics. See: APS Proceedings, vol. 30, p. 116.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Feb. 27, 1892; 7x4-1/2; Potts, William John, 1842-1895
    Camden, N.J., A.L.S. 1p. Accepts appointment to write obituary of J.F. Garrison.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Feb. 27, 1892; 8-1/4x5-1/2; Tatham, W. P. (William P.)
    Phila., A.L.S. 2p. and end. Asks Library Committee to consider exchange of copies of Pennsylvania laws.
  - Letter to H[enry] Philips [sic], March 2, 1892; 7x4-1/2; Bonwill, William Gibson Arlington, 1833-1899
    Phila., A.L.S. 2p. Will read his paper on evolution on March 4. Asks that E.D. Cope be prevented from monopolizing the time.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, March 2, 1892; 8x5; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    [Phila.], L. 3p., end. Enc. wanting. Concerns Cope's amendment to By-Laws, about meetings (Chap.9, No.1). About Bonwill's reading of paper on evolution. Encloses note from Brinton with text of resolution on Columbian celebration.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, March 2, 1892; 3-1/4x5-1/4; Price, John Sergeant, 1831-1897
    Phila., Printed L. filled in in MS. 1p. Asks about dues of McMaster, Wayland.
  - Letter to Henry Philips, March 3, 1892; United States. Post Office Dept.
    1p. T.L.S. regretting annoyance caused by mis-handled postcard. Assures Philips that "If it were possible to ascertain who sent the card to the West Philadelphia Office, the person wold be dismissed from the service."
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, March 3/15, 1892; 6x5; Shmurlo, Vladimir
    St. Petersburg, A.L.S. on postal card 1p. and add. In Esperanto. Asks for publications.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, March 4, 1892; 3-3/4x6-1/4; Lea Brothers & Company
    Phila., Typed L. on postal card 1p. and add. Will stop exchanging American Journal of the Medical Sciences for APS Transactions.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, March 8, 1892; 10-1/2x8; Geological Society of America
    Rochester, N.Y., L. 1p., end. Acknowledges receipt of publications.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, March 8, 1892; 8-1/4x5; Williams, Talcott, 1849-1928
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Acknowledges appointment to committee on publication of transcripts of Babylonian tablets.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, March 9, 1892; 10-1/2x8; American association of electrical engineers
    New York, Typed L.S.: Ralph W. Pope, Secretary. 1p., end. Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, March 9, [1892]; 3x5; Du Bois, Patterson, 1847-1917
    [Phila.], A.L.S. on postal card 1p. and add., end. Illness prevents him from meeting with committee on Assyrian tablets.
  - Letter to the Secretaries of the A.P.S., March 10, 1892; 9x5-3/4; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    Phila., A.L.S. 2p. Concerns printing of a paper. Refers to G. Baur.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, March 14, 1892; 7x4-1/2; Ruschenberger, W. S. W. (William Samuel Waithman), 1807-1895
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Postpones reading of his sketch of Joseph Leidy.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, March 16, 1892; 8x5; Price, John Sergeant, 1831-1897
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Sends certificates. Refers to H.L. Wayland, F. Gutekunst.
  - Receipt for Houdon busts of Franklin and Lafayette, March 18, 1892; 9x5-3/4; Williams, Talcott, 1849-1928
    D.S. 1p. and add., end. Borrowed for University Lecture Association exhibition.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, March 19, 1892; 8x5; Williams, Talcott, 1849-1928
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Arranges delivery of Houdon busts of Franklin and Lafayette to Academy of Fine Arts, for University Lecture Association exhibition.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, March 21, 1892; 10x8; United States. Post Office, Philadelphia
    Phila., Typed L.S.: John Field, Postmaster. 1p., end. Enc. wanting. Sends information on postage for diplomas.
  - Letter to the [American philosophical society], March 22, 1892; 7-3/4x5, 4-1/2x3-1/2; Flower, William Henry, 1831-1899
    London, A.L.S. 3p. Enc. pasted to letter. Concerns Proceedings, and sends list of those he has not received. Refers to British Museum.
  - Letter to the [the American philosophical society], March 22, 1892; 8-1/4x5-1/4; Königlich Preussisches Geodätisches Institut
    Potsdam, Printed L. 1p., end., and fragment of add., end., pasted to letter In German Change of address.
  - Letter to the Secretaries of the A.P.S., March 23, 1892; 6-1/4x3-3/4; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    Phila., A.L.S. on postal card 1p. and add. Concerns printing of his paper for the Transactions.
  - Letter to the [American philosophical society], March 23, 1892; 3-3/4x5-3/4; Schwarz, J. H.
    Kladno, A.L.S. on postal card 1p., end., and add., end. In German Asks receipt for printed matter and letter.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, March 25, 1892; 3x5; Barker, George F. (George Frederick), 1835-1910
    [Phila.], A.L.S. on postal card 1p. and add. Concerns publication of forms. Refers to G.H. Horn.
  - Letter to H[enry] Phillips, March 26, 1892; 3-1/4x5-1/4; Price, John Sergeant, 1831-1897
    Phila., Printed L. filled in in MS. 1p. Asks for copy of Charter and By-Laws.
  - Letter to Henry Philips, March 26, 1892; Norris, Isaac
    1 postcard.
  - Letter to the Secretaries of the A.P.S., March 28, 1892; 8-1/4x5-1/4; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. and end. Concerns his papers on the osteology of Lacertilia, and on little-known Paleozoic fishes. For printed paper on Lacertilia, see: APS Proceedings, vol. 30, pp.185-221. For paper on fishes, see:APS Proceedings, vol. 30, pp.221-229.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, March 29, 1892; 8-1/2x5-1/4; Harvard University
    Cambridge, Mass., A.L.S.: W[illia]m C[oolidge] Lane. 1p., end. Concerns inclusion of A.P.S. MSS. in his Notes on special Collections in American Libraries. Asks for Part IV of the Catalogue.
  - Letter to H[enry] Phillips, March 29, 1892; 7x4-1/2; Ruschenberger, W. S. W. (William Samuel Waithman), 1807-1895
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Will read his sketch of Leidy on April 1st.
  - Letter to [Robert] Patterson, April 2, 1892; 9x5-3/4; Phillips, Henry, 1838-1895
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p., end. with Patterson's reply. Asks to remove A.P.S. possessions from storage in vault of Fidelity Insurance Co.
  - Letter to Frederick Fraley, April 4, 1892; 10-1/2x8; Pepper, William, 1843-1898
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p. Will write obituary of D.H. Agnew.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, April 4, 1892; 7x4-1/2; Ruschenberger, W. S. W. (William Samuel Waithman), 1807-1895
    Phila., A.L.S. 4p. Concerns his sketch of Leidy. Refers to dispute among Cope, Lesley and Marsh.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, April 4, [1892?]; 8x5; Cattell, James McKeen, 1860-1944
    New York, A.L.S. 1p., end. Change of address.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, April 5, 1892; 11x8-1/2; California Academy of Sciences
    San Francisco, Cal., A.L.S.: Carlos Troyer, Librarian. 1p., end., and end. Concerns exchange of publications.
  - Letter to H[enry] Phillips, April 5, 1892; 9x5-3/4; Patterson, Robert, 1819?-1909
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. and add. Concerns repairs to a bookcase.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, April 5, 1892; 6-3/4x4-1/2; Price, John Sergeant, 1831-1897
    Atlantic City, N.J., A.L.S. 2p. and end. Requests copy of one of Fraley's speeches. Refers to A.P.S. centennial celebration.
  - Letter to the [Secretaries of the A.P.S.], April 7, 1892; 9x5-1/2; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    Phila., A.L.S. 2p. Concerns illustrations for a paper, on "Some Little-known Paleozoic Vertebrates." For printed paper, see: A.P.S. Proceedings, vol. 30, pp.221-9.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, April 8, 1892; 7x4-1/2; Potts, William John, 1842-1895
    Camden, N.J., A.L.S. 2p. Cannot meet with Library Committee. Has secured two books for the library. Refers to E.J. Houston.
  - Letter to Henry Philips [sic], April 9, 1892; 10-1/2x8; Blodget, Lorin, 1823-1901
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p. Asks to use the library, which has Works available nowehere else.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, April 9, 1892; 8x5; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    [Phila.], L. 2p. Enc. wanting. Sends Pepper's acceptance to write obituary of Agnew. Adds. I. Horner, J.A. Ryder to Columbian Committee, at Brinton's suggestion. Awaits Lesley's reply about obituary of Pardee.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, April 12, 1892; 7x4-1/2; University lecture association, Philadelphia
    [Phila.], A.L.S.: Caroline Lewis 2p. Thanks for loan of Houdon busts of Lafayette and Franklin for exhibition.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, April 14, 1892; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Union géographique du nord de la France, Douai
    Douai, A.L.S.: Cam. Renour, Secrétaire général. 1p., end. Thanks for Proceedings.
  - Letter to [Henry Phillips], April 14, 1892; 10-1/2x8; United States. Dept. of the Interior
    Washington, Typed L. 2p., end. Lists govt. publications being sent to supply deficiencies in A.P.S. library.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, April 15, 1892; 9x5-3/4; Morris, J. Cheston (James Cheston), 1831-1923
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Has sketch of his work on Aztec MSS. ready for D.G. Brinton. Refers to P. DuBois and the Numismatic Collection.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, April 20, 1892; 3x5-1/4; Boston Athenaeum
    Boston, Printed L. filled in in MS., on postal card. 1p. and add., end. Suggests A.P.S. subscribe to its bulletin of accessions.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, April 21, 1892; 3x5; Morison, Ella M.
    [Phila.], A.L.S. on postal card 1p. and add. Too sick to work.
  - Letter to C[harles] A[mmi] Cutter, Boston, April 22, 1892; 11x8-1/2; Phillips, Henry, 1838-1895
    Phila., L. 1p. Copy. Concerns subscription to Boston Athenaeum's bulletin of accessions.
  - Letter to Frederick Fraley, April 23, 1892; 8x5; Ingham, William A. (William Armstrong), 1827-1913
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Will write obituary of A. Pardee.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, April 25, 1892; 8x5; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    [Phila.], L. 1p. Enc. wanting. Sends W.A. Ingham's acceptance to write obituary of A. Pardee.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, April 26, 1892; 3x5-1/4; Smithsonian Institution
    Washington, Printed L. filled in in MS. 1p. and add., end. Will forward packages.
  - Letter to the [Secretaries of the A.P.S.], April 27, 1892; 9x5-1/2; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    Phila., A.L.S. 2p. Concerns additions to a paper being printed. Refers to McCalla & Co.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, April 27, 1892; 9x6; Heilprin, Angelo, 1853-1907
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p., end., and end. Uncertain if he has seen receipt signed by J. Leidy which J.C. Morris speaks of.
    Not found May, 2011.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, April 27, 1892; 7x4-1/2; Potts, William John, 1842-1895
    Camden, N.J., A.L.S. 2p. Concerns his articles on the alliterative alphabet and on Indian variants. Refers to W.W. Newell, American folklore journal, Library Committee.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, April 28, 1892; 8-1/2x5-1/4; Lane, William Coolidge, 1859-1931
    Cambridge, Mass., A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. Concerns A.P.S. section in his Notes on Special Collections in American Libraries.
    Not Found: 4/2011
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, April 29, 1892; 8x5; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    [Phila.], L. 2p. Enc. wanting. Sends Leland's acceptance of membership. Sends text of resolution recalling Society's collections from places of deposit
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, April 30, 1892; 10-1/2x8; Smithsonian Institution
    Washington, Typed L.S.: S.P. Langley. 1p., end. Concerns package for William Stubbs.
  - Letter to the [American philosophical society], April, 1892; 11-1/4x9; Württembergische Kommission für Landesgeschichte
    Stuttgart, Printed L. 1p., end. In German Change of address. Will publish Württ. Vierteljahrshefte für landesgeschichte.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, May 2, 1892; 10-1/2x8; Hazen, Henry Allen, 1849-1900
    Washington, A.L.S. 1p., end. Asks about Phillips prize essay.
  - Letter to McCalla & Co., Phila., May 3, 1892; 3x5; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    Phila., A.L.S. on postal card 1p. and add. Concerns order in which papers by G. Baur are to appear in the Proceedings.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, May 4, [1892]; 3x5; Brinton, Daniel Garrison, 1837-1899
    Phila., A.L.S. on postal card 1p. and add. Sends paper on Fuegian languages. For paper, see: APS Proceedings, vol. 30, pp.249-254.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, May 5, [1892]; 6x4; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    [Phila.], L. 2p. Probably cannot attend next meeting.
  - Report on Society's collections at present stored outside the Hall, May 6, 1892; 11x8-1/2; American Philosophical Society. Curators
    [Phila.,] Typed D.S.: Patterson DuBois, R[ichard] Meade Bache, J[ames] Cheston Morris 2p., end. (see A.P.S. Curators. Reports) Particularly concerns the numismatic and the Poinsett collections. Cf. Proceedings, v.30, p.262.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, May 6, 1892; 11x8-1¨2; Kansas State Historical Society
    Topeka, Kan., Typed L. 1p., end. Asks for publications to complete its set.
  - Letter to Enrique [sic] Phillips, May 9, 1892; 8x5; Sociedad cientifica "Antonio Alzate"
    Mexico, A.L.S.: Rafael Aguilar. 2p., end. Asks for certain issues of the Proceedings.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, May 11, 1892; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Popular science monthly
    New York, L. 1p., end. Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, May 11, 1892; 3x5-1/4; Potts, William John, 1842-1895
    Camden, N.J., A.L.S. on postal card 1p. and add. Will attend next meeting of Library Committee.
  - Notice to the American philosophical society of change in address, May 19, 1892; 3x4-3/4; Williams, Talcott, 1849-1928
    [Phila.,] Printed D. on postal card 1p. and add.
  - Letter to Edwin J[ames] Houston, May 23, 1892; 9x5-3/4; Phillips, Henry, 1838-1895
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p., end., and end. Concerns purchase of a list of books.
  - Letter to [Henry Phillips;], May 24, 1892; 8x5; Clark, Clarence H. (Clarence Howard), 1833-1906